🛮 (650) 995-6779 | 🔀 romyaboudarham@gmail.com | 🛅 romy-aboudarham

Profile

Versatile creative technologist with inventive intuitions when approaching challenges; always bringing an artistic joyful style to every environment worked at. Passionate about using technology as a tool for telling meaningful stories that engage, educate, inspire, and build community.

Projects.

Virtual Reality Empathy Machine

San Francisco, CA

FINAL PROJECT FOR CLASS XR: IMMERSIVE EXPERIENCES AND SCRIPTED SPACES

Fall 2024

- Empathy-Driven Storytelling, VR Design, and Technical Implementation in Unity
- · Unity, C#, Oculus VR, Story-boarding

Augmented Reality Narrative Journalism

San Francisco, CA

MIDTERM PROJECT FOR CLASS XR: IMMERSIVE EXPERIENCES AND SCRIPTED SPACES

Fall 2024

Augmented Reality Application for Vienna's Museum of Applied Arts

Boston, MA

ASSIGNMENT AT CUSEUM Summer 2018

- Created an application that projected a model of Gustav Klimt's "Tree of Life" on any horizontal surface, casting real time shadows on the ground.
- Taught myself Blender, a 3D modeling software, in a short amount of time to scale, animate, and texture a model.
- Conducted numerous tests and assembled the application into a portfolio to give to the client.

Work Experience

California College of the Arts

San Francisco, CA

LAB MANAGER, INTERACTIVE ELECTRONIC AND DIGITAL ART

November 2022 - Present

- · Guided students in bringing their ideas to life through web/app prototypes, games, wearable IoT designs, interactive installations, and AR/VR experiences.
- · Streamlined lab operations by creating starter kits and utilizing GitHub for project collaboration and tutorials.
- · Managed the lab's budget, designed its floor plan, and coordinated with faculty and teams to enhance its impact.
- · Hired, trained, and managed a team of 10+ work-study students, establishing a structured task system and providing comprehensive technical onboarding in electronics and coding.

META (Facebook) Menlo Park, CA

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER - CONTRACT POSITION

July 2020 - October 2021

- Implemented workflows on Facebook's Single Review Tool which were built using Hack, XML, Data Loggers, and MySQL database.
- Collaborated extensively with data scientists and human labeling teams to design workflows to keep kids safe on Messenger Kids platform.
- Wrote and executed data pipelines in Python.
- · On-boarding and working entirely virtual on a young team at a big company taught me how to navigate an extensive code base on my own and take initiative to reach out to anyone for help.

Armorblox Cupertino, CA

Delivered Two-Factor Authentication APIs and integrated Malicious URL detection.

July 2019 - March 2020

- Designed and implemented methods for grouping and displaying email threats to users.
- · Defined and implemented REST APIs in Golang with gRPC and Protocol Buffers.
- Thrived in a fast-paced startup environment, balancing independent work with cross-team collaboration.

Skills

BACKEND DEVELOPER

COMPUTER SOFTWARE SKILLS

• Unity · C# · C++ · Node.js · Python · HTML/CSS/JS · AFrame · Blender · GIMP · Hack/PHP · Go

SKILLS

• Leadership & Teamwork Skills · Attention to Detail · Creative and Proactive Problem Solver · Rapid Prototyper · Computer and Software proficiency · Multi-dimensional Artistic Abilities · People Skills · Teaching

Education

Tufts University Medford, MA

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING)

2015 - 2019

• Programming Languages · Machine Structure & Assembly Language · Algorithms & Data Structures · Web Programming · Computational Design · Psychology Engineering · Electrical Engineering · Figure Drawing